[Music]
winter has finally come in full force
the lake is quickly turning to ice and
i've noticed the eagles have been busy
seeking to hunt one last time in the
little pools of unfrozen water before a
long unforgiving winter sets in
[Music]
do
i'm spending a lot of time with my
family this december as we come together
to celebrate the end of the year
my mother spent well over 20 years
following my father around the world to
different military bases and she has
always dreamed of having a little house
in a secluded area
at long last she finally got it and i'm
so happy they can enjoy a quiet
retirement here
[Music]
do
while i was at their house i found a
very interesting book
it was about mostly forgotten words that
describe unusual feelings
for example heartsburg which is
explained to be a noun for an unexpected
surge of feelings brought about by an
ordinary thing
for example a certain smell or the sound
of a creaking door
a train whistle in the distance i
related to this and another word in
particular known as anamoya
it means nostalgia for a time you never
experienced
[Music]
i really love this word i can relate to
it
as a child i used to have dreams about a
great forest full of light and color and
a vibrance that seemed to pulsate to a
heartbeat deep in the roots of the trees
in that place i felt an overwhelming
sense of love everywhere
that dream never physically existed but
it has stayed with me as a place i yearn
for always
it is a memory that comforts me and
reminds me to seek out the light
no matter how dark the winter days
become
[Music]
i once read an article that commented on
how there is a great void in the english
language in regards to describing the
complexity of emotions
for example a word in this book was
marumori which in essence was described
to mean the heartbreaking simplicity of
ordinary things
and i love that description because it
really nails down a feeling i've always
had about the beauty of the mundane and
the ordinary
even during the coldest loneliest months
there is artistry around us waiting to
be appreciated both nature's and
man-made
everything from the paintings i create
to the glitter of the snow under the
light of a full moon
[Music]
it is a heartbreaking sort of beauty
when truly appreciated i think because
it pulls us back to a time perhaps when
it was easier for us to enjoy simply
living or another possibility that it
gives that elusive animoya a yearning
for reality we innately know yet cannot
grasp
our human nature will always leave us
unable to enjoy the present every day
real life gets involved and things get
messy and that's okay we cannot avoid it
though we can have moments of being
truly grateful for what we do have
[Music]
to paraphrase a quote from an admired
philosopher c.s lewis if we find
ourselves with a desire this world can't
satisfy
a possible explanation is that we were
not made for this world
now i don't expect everyone to believe
this is true i think there are many
compelling explanations for this feeling
either way i think it is a good reminder
that there is a lot out there that
cannot yet be explained
so many mysteries worth considering
[Music]
iger is sleeping right next to my feet
so
we'll see if he behaves himself
you're gonna behave yourself
yeah
maybe
oh my goodness
we got gosh it seems like a foot of snow
in one day it's it's amazing
it's just so beautiful
and
honestly i kind of just put aside all my
plans just to spend some time enjoying
it the first snow is always just so
magical
as you can see i'm at my parents house
we are planning to play a lot of board
games this week my sister is coming i
think in about a week as well from
houston texas and i'm just so excited to
see her and spend some time with her we
haven't seen her for a while now and i'm
just so excited for her to come over
here and enjoy some snow
and we're hopefully going to go sledding
and hiking and skiing and we'll we'll
see what we get up to it's going to be
really fun i've recently been reading
about all the different traditions and
holidays that happen this time of year
and it is just amazing how many are out
there i wrote down some of the main ones
i'm sure there are a lot more
there is of course christmas which is
extremely popular there's also i was
reading about soyal
which seems to be a fascinating holiday
i don't know much about it but i do want
to learn a little more
kwanzaa
hanukkah
which is a holiday i'd heard about but i
didn't realize how popular it was so i
really enjoyed learning about that one
and of course there's also the west
winter solstice or yule and gosh there's
just so many other ones it's so
wonderful to learn about all the
different traditions
and
celebrations this time of year it is so
beautiful you know i've always thought
that you know if we all celebrate the
same things then the world would be just
so much less interesting and less full
of interesting stories so i've i've
really enjoyed learning about all these
celebrations this time of year so if you
are celebrating something this year
please let me know what you're
celebrating i'm very excited to learn
about all these new traditions some of
them which i've not heard about before
reading about these traditions got me
more interested in reading some more
taino legends i was reading a taino myth
about the son of a very powerful being
in taino mythology the powerful being's
name was atabay
and she had a son called jukajiu jukaju
wanted to give the darkness of the night
more beauty and so he went down into the
deepest caverns and he took out
gemstones and he went up and he put the
gemstones into the sky and the gemstones
reflected the light of the sun and moon
and created the night sky and all the
constellations and all the stars and i
thought that was such a beautiful way
and creative way to describe the night
sky and how in this myth it was made i
thought it was so beautiful i think it
is so important
to have respect and reverence for these
stories that were so important to so
many groups of people in the past and
sometimes even in the present
and i've just found a lot of inspiration
from reading those old myths and legends
from from all over the world even celtic
myths and legends on my father's side of
the family he has a lot of european
ancestry and a lot of celtic ancestry
and so reading as well the myths of that
area as well has been so fascinating and
it is so exciting to just connect with
the past and connect with stories anyway
i'm just so excited to have my family
together this month to play games any
good food and make coquito and just have
such a wonderful time so it's gonna be
it's gonna be lovely and i am sure we're
gonna get probably another foot of snow
before the month is out so i'm
anticipating to be quite snowden for a
while so that will be wonderful
there is a book i mention in this video
called the dictionary of obscure sorrows
and i thought it was such a funny title
but once i picked up the book and i
started reading it i found it to be
incredible it had so many interesting
words and phrases that are rarely used
or no longer used or at the very least
not used in the english language very
much
and i found it really fun to read about
it one word i i can't remember what the
word exactly was
but it pretty much was meant to describe
the nostalgic
feel that you get when you hear
a train whistle in the distance
and how that often gives you a sense of
wanderlust and i thought that was such
an interesting word to describe a
feeling that i think a lot of us can
relate to
i thought it i thought it was really fun
lastly i wanted to say thank you for all
the wonderful birthday wishes it was
a really lovely week i actually received
some very meaningful gifts and i have
not been able to get in contact with
all the gift givers so if your name is
tammy
i want to say thank you very much for
the gift you left for me
it was very meaningful and very
unexpected and a wonderful surprise and
i
have your name but i cannot find any way
to contact you and tell you thank you
personally so if you're seeing this know
that i'm very very grateful also a
lovely artist known as eve
sent me a beautiful meditation orb that
i will show you some images it is so
beautiful i've shown her work before
but um
she sent me this one unexpectedly and it
happened to align with my birthday which
i don't think she intended but it was
really fun anyway i just counted it as a
birthday gift and it was it was really
lovely to receive and it is just
beautiful so i will leave a link to her
work down below in case you want to see
more of her carvings they're just
absolutely gorgeous
since i wasn't feeling too great i've
gotten quite behind on some replies and
some messages i've been meaning to send
so i apologize for that if you've been
kept waiting i've been doing my best
it's been a very busy month as you can
see in this video i've been working so
hard on creating a lot of new art pieces
and trying to get them all finished for
a big book project i'm working on
it has just been a huge
feat so
i am doing my best and trying to get on
top of things
but we'll see anyway i hope you're doing
well
i know that the holidays can be a
sometimes difficult time for a lot of
people depending on what your family
life is like and where you are in life
and what your hopes are for the new year
i'm sending you hugs and hope that you
can find some moments of peace and joy
this month i know usually it can feel
quite hectic but i hope that the new
year will provide a lot of incredible
new opportunities
and some new beginnings and a time to
winter
and to
come into the spring with new life and
new excitement and enthusiasm so
i will see you guys soon
i'm sending my love goodbye